You've heard Alvin come up with several conclusions for how to
set up the program. And we're going to ask that you follow his
instincts. We'll spell that out here in a little more technical details
so that everyone is working from the same basic starting point. The
program must be written in Java and must not make you any
nonstandard Java libraries. You will be tested on a machine with the
vanilla installation of Java 1.6. Your program must compile on the command
line using the Java C command without any additional options. All code
required to execute the program that is not part of the
standard JDK, must be included as source code with your program.
Your program should be an application. That is, it should have
a main method and should be executable from the command line using
the Java command. The user should be able to provide a
file path to the file they wish to be analyzed as a
command line argument. User should be able to specify which delimiters
count as sentence separators, using the flag -d, defaulting to Lauren's initial
thoughts on what should be used as delimiters. The user should be
able to specify a lower limit for word length, using the flag -l,
defaulting to Lauren's guess at what value might be good. Finally, the program's
output should be the average sentence
length. Rounded down to the nearest integer.